Wahyu Setianto

Ciracas, East Jakarta, 13740 | 081314761132 | wahyusetianto19@gmail.com | github.com/Hyuto | hyuto.github.io

Data Enthusiast

Final year student majoring in Statistics at State University of Jakarta. I have a deep interest in data. I believe with decision made based on data can have more impact in solving problems in real world. I have a lot of experience in processing data to gain insight and solve problems with various method (such as *machine learning, deep learning, nlp, etc.*). I have deep knowledge on several data analysis tools such as Python and R. I am also interested in *web development* to create a website as a hobby.

Experience

PT Ivonesia Solusi Data (Ivosights)

July 2021 – October 2021

Operation & Data

Preparing brand report projects by making analytical reports from several social media platform within 6-month period using *descriptive statistics*, *data visualization*, *forecasting*, and *sentiment analysis* to gain insight from data.

Bangkit Academy by Google

February 2021 - July 2021

Machine Learning Student

Learning about materials that have been prepared in path of *machine learning* using Tensorflow. Responsible for completing the final project to built an application using *mobile*, *cloud*, and *machine learning* technology.

Education

State University of Jakarta

2018 - Present

Statistics

• GPA: 3.54 /4.00

BIDIKMISI scholarship (2018 – Present)

58 Jakarta High School

2015 - 2018

Mathematics and Science

Technical Skill Set

Programming Language	Skills		Operating Systems		Other Tech	
Python	•	Machine Learning (Supervised & Unsupervised)	•	Windows	•	VSCode
• R	•	Deep Learning (Tensorflow)	•	Linux (Ubuntu)	•	Rstudio Ms. Excel
 SQL 	•	Forecasting				
 Javascript 	•	Data Visualization				
 Typescript 						

Achievement

Finalist | Group October 2021

Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2021 (National)

Puspresnas & IPB University

Classifying gender and detect a person's age based on image data.

2nd place & Best Metric Performance | Group

October 2020

Lomba Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2020 (National)

Puspresnas & IPB University

Classifying hoaxes based on image data and text data from news.

Organization

BPRS ERAFM UNJ March 2020 – January 2021

Creative Design

Certification

TensorFlow: Data and Deployment Specialization May 2021

Coursera

DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer Specialization April 2021

Coursera

Google IT Automation with Python Specialization March 2021

Coursera

Certificate of Stargazer June 2020

CodeAbbey

Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science January 2019

Digital Talent Scholarship

Projects

Gender & Age Detection | Group

November 2021

Create a model with the aim of classifying gender and detecting a person's age from image data. This project was carried out to solve the challenges of Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2021

RangRang | Group June 2021

Mobile application that aims to teach children to identify objects around them in English. RangRang is an application that combines 3 elements, namely mobile development, cloud computing, and machine learning. This project was carried out as the final project of Bangkit 2021.

Hoax Classification | Group

November 2020

Create a model with the aim of classifying Hoax based on the text and image data. This project was carried out to solve the challenges of the Big Data Competition – Satria Data 2020.

Analysis of DKI Jakarta's Corona Twitter Sentiment

April 2020

Create a model to classify public opinion that is poured out on Twitter social media related to the topic of "corona" in the DKI Jakarta area and its surroundings.